hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist
and we are talking about API testing now
we have looked at many features
available in the Tosca API scan
and today I am going to show you how you
can add different attachments to your
API message through API scan okay so
let's go ahead and create a new message
here API message and I'm going to call
it
test attachment
okay
and for this we are going to use a
endpoint this is a sample endpoint which
is available in Postman okay it is the
Eco service which is used to test
different features of Postman it's a
sample API service which is available
with Postman okay
so I'm going to use this endpoint okay
and we have to change the method to post
okay
and then we need to go to the
attachments tab okay so from the payload
you will see there is a attachments tab
here and uh here you can specify the
name file content type right and here
you can also load from a file okay so
when you click on file there will be a
load button which will appear here with
three ellipses click on that and it will
ask you to upload the file which you
want to attach okay say for example I
want to attach this Json source file
okay so I'm going to click on open
and then the content type will be
automatically uh displayed here so Tosca
EPS can will automatically detect what
is the content type
and then the name will also appear here
I can obviously I can change this but
let in V for now okay
so you can see you can load the file
from here and then automatically all the
other fields will be provided here okay
now there are some additional options
here like content transfer encoding
content type omit file name okay so you
can do that you can omit the file name
and you can also enable m2om
now frankly I am not aware what is this
but I can check back and provide this in
the comments if you require this okay
but for now uh this is what we are going
to do we are going to attach this file
uh with this particular API message and
we are going to run this now
and you will see that in the status code
we'll get a 200 okay and in the payload
so this particular API message it just
gets back the complete
content of your attachment file okay so
this is the file content of the file
which we have attached obviously it is
encoded so you cannot see what is there
in that particular content which is
being returned by the response right
but uh this is how uh for API messages
where you need to send Maybe
a file a image or anything right you can
attach that file or you can send an
attachment right from your request okay
you can just browse for the file and
then uh you have some additional options
and after that you can just send the
message and you will get back the
response
so it's a very simple way of uh
basically attaching different files
which are required for your particular
API message
and that's all for this short video
I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new do tune into our channel
to watch more videos on trash and
testoster and API testing using the
Tosca API scan